

Address

B/2, Kaushlendra Nagar, Tejendra Nagar Part -3, Near New Railway Colony, Sabarmati, Ahmedabad - 19.

Contact

+91 - 7600184676 mrhrarora@gmail.com

PROFILE

Date of Birth 22.04.1991

10 years demonstrated experience in a corporate business analysis function. Proficient in prioritisation, requirements elicitation, cataloguing and process mapping for businesses. Demonstrates an advanced level of critical thinking, evaluation and interpretation.

SKILLS

Team Management

Leadership

Excellent Conceptual and Analytical Skills

Critical Observation

Establishing Interpersonal Relationships

Strategic Business Planning

Business and Market Analysis

Willingness to Learn

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Microsoft Excel

Macro

VBA

Power BI

PostgreSQL

SAP - MM

LANGUAGES

HOBBY







Music Football

Travelling

HEMANT R ARORA

MIS & Human Resource Analysts

Linkedin

inkedin.com/in/hemant-r-arora-51848072

EDUCATION

04.2008 - 06.2011

Aroma College of Commerce, Ahmedabad

Bachelor of Commerce

11.2021 - 01.2022

University of California, Irvine

Human Resources Analytics - Coursera

EXPERIENCE

05.2021 - 08.2021

Alept Consulting Pvt Ltd., Ahmedabad

Business Analysts - Human Resources

- Collecting data on payroll outputs, management and employee surveys, employment records, and exit interviews.
- Implementing relevant HR metrics in order to determine the efficiency and impact of the workforce.
- Review & Analyze the Data/Trackers.

09.2020 - 04.2021

Flagrant Services LLP, Ahmedabad

Senior Data Analysts - Human Resources

- Optimizing and implementing new data processes and systems.
- Compiling reports of data results and presenting these to senior managers.
- Identifying short- and long-term goals to ensure topnotch employee performance.
- Recommending policies that will improve the culture within the company and suggest ways in which to hire the best candidates for the job.
- Identifying why candidates and employees choose to work within a company and recommending areas in the workplace that can be improved.

09.2019 - 09.2020

Dainik Bhaskar Group, Ahmedabad

National MIS Head - Ad Sales

- Business planning & strategy.
- Design, developed and analysis of ad sales MIS.
- Coordination with MDO team for deal, rate contract & scheme approval.

CAAFT

- Capability to draw Business insights and able to present it to management.
- Prepare KRA for sales team.

PROJECT - VBA CODING

Prepare automatic excel order booking form for Shree Ganesh Decorators for function booking.

02.2017 - 09.2019

Godrej & Boyce Mfg. Co. Ltd., Pune

Senior MIS Executive - Logistics

- Utilize logistics IT to optimize procedures.
- Coordinate and monitor supply chain operations.
- Prepare accurate reports for upper management.
- Keep logs and records of warehouse stock, executed orders etc.
- Plan and track the shipment of final products according to customer requirements.
- Recruit and coordinate logistics staff according to availabilities and requirements.

12.2015 - 01.2017

Adani Green Energy Ltd., Ahmedabad

MIS Executive - Human Resources

- Designing the brief KRAs / JDs after understanding the position from the Reporting Manager.
- Posting the job on Naukri / other portals and using Social Media like LinkedIn.
- Screening & short-listing profiles and share with the Reporting Manager.
- Maintaining and timely update of Personnel File and keeping an internal check / review.
- HR MIS preparation & implementation in consultation with Reporting Manager.
- Joining Formalities, Background Verification, Exit Formalities & Medical Test Formalities.

07.2013 - 11.2015

Dainik Bhaskar Group, Ahmedabad

MIS Executive - Ad Sales

- Preparation & analysis of various marketing reports.
- Planning of target for coming months & many more.
- Coordinating entire Gujarat State for compilation of various reports for higher management.
- Prepare kra for sales team.
- Prepare state incentives on quarterly basis.

06.2011 - 07.2013

Abellon Clean Energy Ltd., Ahmedabad

Junior MIS Officer - Audit

- Responsible for database management of all types of vouchers.
- Responsible for the review and monitor of data regarding accounts payable payments & budget expense.
- Worked as part of the group audit team, primarily verifies financial operations.
- Responsible for auditing of physical stock audit.

REFERENCE

Available on Request

